在最后一个模块中，我们处理了一个 about 页面
in the last module we handled an about page
我可以想象有其他静态页面的路线
and I can imagine having routes for other static pages
可能是联系页面或 f 页面
maybe a contact page or an f page
是的，并为每个页面提供服务
yeah and to serve each of those pages
我们首先
we'd first
需要获取 pages 目录的绝对路径
need to get the absolute path to the pages directory
就像我们对关于页面所做的那样
as we did with the about page
所以分享这段代码
so to share this bit of code
我们可以将它提取到一个函数中
we could extract it into a function
但是页面目录的路径是一个常量
but the path to the pages directory is a constant
这让我们有机会学习一些东西
which gives us an opportunity to learn something
关于模块的新内容
new about modules
模块可以有属性
modules can have attributes
模块属性定义在
module attributes are defined at the
模块的顶层
top level of a module
总的来说
and in general
您可以使用模块属性来关联元数据
you can use module attributes to associate metadata
与模块
with the module
例如长生不老药有
for example elixir has
两个保留的模块属性
two reserved module attributes
用于记录模块和功能
for documenting modules and functions
模块的文档位于
the documentation for a module goes at the
模块顶部
top of the module
并且模块属性的名称是 module dock
and the name of the module attribute is module dock
你注意到它以 at 符号开头
and you notice it starts with an at sign
这表明它是一个模块属性
that indicates that it's a module attribute
然后因为它是文档
and then because it's documentation
我们可以给它一个字符串
we can give it a string
所以说处理http请求
so say handles http requests
现在你可以在这里使用它
now you can use it here
文档
doc
并在字符串中添加更多文档
and add a bunch more documentation here in the string
但我会保持它真的
but I'm going to just keep it really
这个截屏视频很简单
simple for this screencast
因为你真的不想看我
because you really don't want to watch me
输入文档
typing in documentation
以便记录模块
so that documents the module
还有一个名为 doc 的模块属性
there's also a module attribute called at doc
记录它下面的函数
that document the function underneath it
所以这个可能是变换
so this one might be transforms
请求
the request
回应
into a response
并且可以设置相同的属性
and the same attribute can be set
在一个模块中多次
multiple times in a module
所以要记录这个函数
so to document this function
我们也会使用
we would also use the
停靠模块属性，然后字符串可能是
dock module attribute and then the string might be
记录四个或四个请求
logs four or four requests
然后使用这些定义明确的属性
and then using these well defined attributes
elixir 可以访问这些值以生成文档
elixir can access the values to generate documentation
所以灵药有
so elixir has
用于文档目的的保留属性
reserved attributes for documentation purposes
我们可以添加
and we can add
任意或自定义模块属性
arbitrary or custom module attributes as well
是的，模块属性的另一个常见用途是
yeah another common use of module attributes is as
常量，这正是我们所拥有的
constants and that's exactly what we have
在这里
down here
我们可以把它变成一个辅音
we can take this and make it a consonant
所以我只是要复制它和模块属性
so I'm just going to copy it and the module attribute
它只需要在模块的顶层定义
it just has to be defined at the top level of module
但你可以把它放在任何地方
but you can put it anywhere
所以我们可以称之为单页路径
and so we can call this one pages path
然后值将是
and then the value will be
该表达式的结果
the result of that expression
然后进入我们的管道
then down in our pipeline
而不是这样做
instead of doing this
我们可以在页面路径中读取该值
we can just read that value at pages path
如果我们有
and if we had
需要读取页面文件的其他路由函数
other route functions that needed to read page files
虽然他们可以使用页面路径属性
while they could use the pages path attribute
什么也不错
what's also nice
是使用常量让我们很容易改变
is that using a constant lets us easily change
页面的位置
the location of the page
目录在一个地方
directory in one place
所以如果我们现在运行它，我们会看到它有效
so if we run it now we see that it works
现在我说你可以添加模块属性
now I said that you can add module attributes
模块顶层的任何位置
anywhere in the top level of module
但我通常将常量放在模块的顶部
but I generally put constants at the top of a module
因为它们的值是在编译时设置的
because their value is set at compile time
所以我要把它带走
so I'm going to take this out of here
我们就把它放在这里
and we'll just put it right up here
在模块底座下
under the module dock
就这样
just like that
所以现在在这一点下定义的任何函数
so now any function defined below this point
可以读取值
can read the value